# Samuel Lee Jackson

Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire

SamuelLeeJackson.co.uk

☑ contact@samuelleejackson.co.uk

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

I am a post-doctoral research associate with an interest in the study of small solar system bodies (comets and asteroids). I focus largely on developing software to characterise asteroids from observations with ground and space-based telescopes, and I have experience in the operation, management and development of astronomical observatories. In my spare time I play cricket and regularly travel around the country to watch Southend United Football Club.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## The Open University

Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire

Post-Doctoral Research Associate

2023 - Current

Developing techniques to characterise the nature of the surfaces of asteroids from thermal-infrared telescope observations. Achieved through thermal modelling of the target bodies and comparison to observations to derive physical properties.

#### University of Edinburgh

Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire (Remote)

Post-Doctoral Research Associate (Part-Time)

2022 - 2023

Researching the aftermath of the NASA DART impact into an asteroid using observations with a portable telescope in Kenya. As part of this role I have also been involved in providing ground work for a future permanent optical telescope in Kenya, which will be the first of its kind in the country.

## The Open University & University of Edinburgh

Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire

Night Duty Astronomer/Emergency Support Astronomer

2019 - 2022 (Multiple Contracts)

Responsible for ensuring safe operation of the OpenScience Observatories during student use for multiple universities. Provided on-call emergency support to allow round-the-clock access to the observatories for the students, resolving hardware and software issues in a timely manner.

## The Open University

Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire

Course Facilitator

February - March 2020

Facilitating discussion and providing expert comment for thousands of students on the Massive Open Online Course 'In the night sky: Orion' on FutureLearn.

## Adams Joinery Ltd.

Leigh-on-Sea, Essex

Dispatch & Quality Control

July-September 2013, 2016, 2017, 2018

# **EDUCATION**

#### PhD in Astronomy & Planetary Science

*The Open University, Milton Keynes* 

2019 - 2023

Astronomy, Space Science, and Astrophysics MPhys (First Class Honours)

University of Kent, Canterbury

2015 - 2019

GCSE & A-Level Education

# **KEY SKILLS**

## Computing skills:

- o Programming languages: Python, C++, CUDA C/C++, MATLAB, Bash
- Operating systems: Linux, Windows

#### Other skills:

- Astronomical observations
- Data analysis and statistics
- Public speaking
- Technical writing
- Working as part of collaborations of all sizes

# AWARDS AND MEMBERSHIPS

- Asteroid 30226 Samuelleejackson (2000 GY137) named after me for my contributions to planetary science (2023)
- Associate Member of the Division for Planetary Sciences of the American Astronomical Society (2022 - Current)
- Rotary Prize for the Faculty of Sciences, University of Kent (2019)
- o Dean's Prize for the Faculty of Sciences, University of Kent (2018)
- o Fellow of the Royal Astronomical Society (2017 Current)

# **PUBLICATIONS**

## Peer reviewed publications:

- Jackson, S. L., Kolb, U. C., & Green, S. F. (2021). Asteroid Photometry with PIRATE: Optimizations and Techniques for Small-Aperture Telescopes. *PASP*, 133, 075003
- Jackson, S. L., Rozitis, B., Dover, L. R., Green, S. F., Kolb, U. C., Andrews, A. E., & Lowry, S. C. (2022). The Effect of Aspect Changes on Near-Earth Asteroid Phase Curves. MNRAS, 513(2), 3076
- Dover, L., Lowry, S. C., Rożek, A, Rozitis, B., Jackson, S. L., et al. (2023). Physical modelling of near-Earth asteroid (23187) 2000 PN9 with ground-based optical and radar observations. MNRAS, in press

# REFERENCES

References/referee contact details available on request.